Peter Gillingham

Email petergillingham80@gmail.com

Phone 07383 014163

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/peter-gillingham

GitHub https://github.com/PeterG184

Personal Statement

I am a software engineer with a broad skillset including full stack web development, machine learning with Python, and embedded systems engineering with C and C++. I graduated from the University of York, awarded an Upper Second Class Honours for an Integrated Masters in Electronic Engineering with Music Systems Technology. In my career so far I have successfully integrated myself into a fast paced environment, working with many technologies across multiple areas of software engineering, including front and back end web development, implementation of AI solutions and assisting in research on networking in embedded devices.

Work Experience

Research Software Engineer

April 2024–Present

University of York, Department of Computer Science

My projects involve developing software for experiments involving embedded devices and developing machine learning models for energy usage and generation in Python. My contributions have been published and presented in conferences in the networking field, including the RIPE88 meeting and the WINCOM'24 conference. I am also a part of the Systron Lab research group, investigating system introperability in networking.

Software Engineer

August 2023–February 2024

Premium Lithium

I worked across many disciplines in this role, developing full stack web applications, leading multiple projects in operations management and internal statistic tracking, and implementing AI applications for energy arbitrage and solar panel detection. It was a fast paced start up requiring me to manage my time effectively, meet ever changing requirements and deadlines, and work as part of an agile team.

Production Operator

October 2021–August 2023

DJ Assembly

I have worked in all areas of production and manufacturing of electronic goods, including circuit assembly, box build, and inspection, testing and validation. I also gained experience in managing outgoing and internal stock and logistics.

Education

Integrated Master's in Electronic Engineering with Music Systems Technology *September 2019–June 2023*

University of York

This course has taught me and improved my knowledge in many areas, including electronics, software development, hardware implementation, embedded system design, networking, digital signal processing and data analysis.

Technical skills

Languages Python, JavaScript/TypeScript (Node.js, React, SvelteKit), C/C++,

C#/.NET, Java and SQL

Technologies Git, Linux, PostgreSQL, AWS, Google Cloud Compute, Vercel

Engineering Circuit Design and Analysis, Hardware and Software Integration,

Embedded System Design and Development

Key Projects

- Investigated vulnerabilities in Thread Network devices, developing a console and GUI utility for controlling embedded devices, and implementing jamming attacks and countermeasures in a testbed thread network.
- Led a project to develop an AI driven energy arbitrage algorithm for use in homes to manage the purchasing and storing of generated energy.
- Set up data collection of a solar farm, including energy and weather data in a Dockerised MySQL database, alongside a web based (React) frontend and Python API for visualisation and data retrieval, and working on energy usage and generation prediction with machine learning models

Interests

I have played guitar for over a decade, drums for four years, and have taken on the role of lead guitarist and audio engineer for my band, resulting in us releasing two albums and playing multiple shows in York. I am also a keen and regular climber, both in climbing gyms and outdoors, and I enjoy cycling in and around York.